Josh Knapp

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

541.368.8091 - joshmk.com - joshknappp@gmail.com (yes 3p's :)

Best described as a React specialist, I shine at developing high-quality user interfaces but can also deliver value across the stack.

My favorite part of this career is seeing the joy and/or relief on a user's face when the software you created solves their problem well. I love simplifying complex needs into very simple and beautiful tools. For my next step, I'd like to work with a high-energy, creative team that is loaded with ideas

Skills

Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, CSS-in-JS, jQuery

Backend

Python, Flask, NodeJS, MySQL, CouchDB, REST APIs, Docker

Testing

Cypress, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library

General

Agile, Lean, Scrum, Azure Devops, GitHub, CI/CD pipelines, PyCharm, VS Code, Chrome Developer Tools, GIT, Git hooks

Experience

ASML / Software Engineer

November 2018 - Present, Hillsboro, OR

Part of an exciting internal software development team delivering a tool for deployment and maintenance of next generation semiconductor lithography machines.

- → Work primarily on the client side (React/Redux)
- → Delivered many integration (cypress) and unit tests (Jest, Enzyme, React-Testing-Library)
- → Advocated for experimentation with new waves of latest technology
- → Key voice in SCRUM ceremonies: stand-ups, retrospectives, plannings, demo's and refinements
- → Collaborated across teams and with external service providers to deliver complex features
- → Represented entire team in demo's for customers and stakeholders
- → Deployed to DTAP environment both manually and via automated pipeline (Azure Pipelines)
- → Provided thoughtful feedback on colleagues work via Pull Requests
- → Advocated for automation wherever possible
- → Estimated work and maintained ticket-closing focus to meet deadlines
- → Greatly enjoyed sharing knowledge via code reviews and mentoring other team members
- → Internalized business goals for technical decision making
- → Technically interviewed >30 people to grow team from 2 to 8 developers
- → Participated in kicking off 2 complementary SCRUM development teams
- → Delivered small tickets on the Backend (Python, Flask, MySQL)
- → Interacted with internal IT to maximize security
- → Used IDE tools VS Code and PyCharm

ASML (Contract) / Software Engineer & Data Analyst

March 2017 - November 2018, Hillsboro, OR

Successfully developed an MVP for maintenance planning software, highlighting a need for internal operations tracking software and kicking off 3 internal software development teams.

- → Delivered world-wide Skills Management dashboard
- → Created local OPEX reports, presented to local management and aligned with engineers at headquarters
- → Traveled internationally to represent greater team

Edge Development / Assistant to Superintendents

December 2016 - March 2017, Portland, OR

Represented Contractors and Superintendents on job sites when they were at other sites.

People Ready / Temp Worker

January 2017 - March 2017, Portland, OR

Worked in 11 different industries.

Marble Technologies / Co-Founder and Creative Director

July 2016 - January 2017, Portland, OR

Grew a profitable website client base from an untapped Portland market.

TriMike Creations / Mechanical Engineering Intern

June 2014 - September 2014, Albany, OR

OSU Robotics & Human Control Systems Lab / Research Assistant

July 2013 - April 2014, Corvallis, OR

Research into autonomous grasping of abstract objects.

- → Utilized Python and open-source robotics technology like ROS and OpenRave to control a 6ft robot arm using a keyboard, floating mouse and game controller
- → Analyzed 3D point cloud data from XBOX Kinects
- → Presented technology to paying customers
- → Tried not to trip over little self-driving robots scanning the room

Eigen Medical / Mechanical Engineering Intern

June 2010 - September 2010 & June 2011 - September 2011, Grass Valley, CA

Education

Oregon State University / B.S. Industrial Engineering, Business Engineering Option, Minor in Business & Entrepreneurship

September 2011 - June 2016, Corvallis, OR

- → Learned the basics of HTML, CSS and JavaScript while receiving mentorship from an experienced React developer for ODOT
- → Utilized Python for robotics research
- → Utilized Matlab for Mechanical engineering simulations
- → Participated in Mars Rover team and Underwater Robotics team